ADAM D'COSTA

JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

BRISTOL, UK

adamdcosta.github.io/adam-dcostaportfolio

TECH STACK

HTML

CSS/SCSS

JAVASCRIPT

REACT

JAVA/SPRING

GIT/GITHUB FLOW

TDD

JEST/CYPRESS/REACT TESTING LIBRARY

EDUCATION

London Metropolitan University (2012) BA(Hons) Illustration – 1st

Stroud College (2009)

Foundation Diploma in Art and Design —

Distinction

KLB School (2001 - 2008)

A Levels - Fine Art(A), Graphic Art (A),

Maths(C), French-AS(B).

INTERESTS

I always have a book on the go, enjoy going for walks and have always been interested in the natural environment. I love eating and cooking good vegan food and follow several sports but particularly football and basketball.

PROFILE

After 8 years of working in bookselling, a desire to build on new skills learnt during lockdown lead me to the decision to retrain and start a new career by enrolling on the twelve-week software development course with _nology. The course gave me the confidence that I've made the right decision to change career; that I relish the prospect of building something that is used by other people and has an impact on their lives. I'm a quick learner with a customer-focused, flexible skillset developed in previous roles, as well as experience working in teams. I'm looking forward to starting my first role in tech.

EXPERIENCE

_nology JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

An intensive 12-week software development course giving me a solid foundation in both front-end and back-end development. The course began with learning HTML, CSS/SCSS and Git/GitHub flow before moving onto Javascript. During the weeks learning Javascript we were set multiple projects which we had to demo to the class each week. This included a morse-code translator written with a TDD approach and unit tests, and a game — of which I did Connect Four. We then moved onto React, building a website using an external API. Java was the focus of the final four weeks, where we built our own API and learned the fundamentals of OOP. We worked on a live client project in which I was product owner for the final week and delivery of the project.

Foyles Bookshop AREA COMMERCIAL SUPPORT

Sept 2019 - July 2021

Supporting shop teams through effective buying, ordering, communication, and training to ensure consistent commercial offers across all departments of the six-floored flagship store. I worked closely with the store management team on specific projects and to drive improvements – for example planning and implementing a new layout of the flagship store in order to drive sales of new and bestselling titles whilst also setting merchandising standards. I acted as a conduit for communication between head office and shop teams.

HEAD OF PROMOTIONS

Sept 2017 - Sept 2019

Responsible for planning, co-ordination and maintenance of the key Front of House and departmental display areas at the flagship store, as well as ordering and negotiating margin. Outlining a strong, title-driven promotional plan, that supports the store and company's overall strategy and works in line with key publishing dates and seasonal peaks. Working on projects with external and internal stakeholders to bring together cross-platform promotions. One of which was a month long promotion with Penguin, including a window display and promotions throughout the shop. Negotiated a 10% increase on margin for the initial spend.

FOYLES BOOKSHOP

May 2013 - Sept 2017

Enjoyed various customer-focused roles including Bookseller, Duty Manager and Supervisor. Whilst working in the Art Department of the flagship store I sourced and bought new titles and used data to change the layout of the department to reflect changing sales patterns.